Welcome to your final serving of donut.
In this part, we are going to be
lighting, rendering, and making our
doughnut actually look good. The final
piece of the puzzle. Um, which is the
most fun, honestly. Um, because
currently it just kind of looks like a
early '90s test render or something.
Very, very bland. So, let's make this
actually look good. Uh, we're going to
be moving around some stuff. And you can
see that if you like move an object, you
always leave behind something, right?
And this is just annoying to deal with.
So to fix this, you parent things to
other things. So for example, if you
want the icing to be connected to the
donut, then you first select the icing,
you shift select the donut, then you hit
controlP
to parent. Um, and there's you can
parent to the object or object keep
transform. I always choose keep
transform otherwise it can like clear
the original location and you kind of
lose its location. So always uh keep
transform and so there you go. So now
when we move the donut um the icing is
going with it. Importantly you'll notice
that in the outliner you can't see the
icing anymore. The icing has gone. Where
is it? And this can be confusing
sometimes. You're like where's that
object? And it's because it's parented
to the donut. So it's now underneath in
this little drop down here. It's in
there. It's also a good idea to use like
what is connected to what as a
hierarchy. So for example, the donut is
connected to the plate. So I'm now going
to select the donut, shift, select the
plate, ctrl P, keep transform. And so
now I can move the donut with the icing
by itself or the plate with the donut.
I'm going to do the same thing for the
foam on top of the mug. Ctrl P. Keep
transform. And then also the plate and
the cup I'm going to parent to the plane
the table. I'm going to say keep
transform. So now all of our objects are
in here, right? They're all parented and
you know they're all found underneath
this. So we got to make sure that it's
actually named correctly. So I'll call
that table. This is going to be called
plate. And
I think we're good. Okay. Excellent. Now
I've actually got two lamps in mine. Um
most of you don't. Uh, you've just got
the one, so I'll just delete that. Um,
but yeah, let's go into lighting. The
fun bit. Actually, making this look
cool. Okay, so we want this to look like
a sunlit cafe. At least I do. You're
welcome to do whatever you want, but if
you want to play along, that's what
we're doing. So, um, with our lamp here
selected, you can see that we've got a
number of different types here. We've
got point, sun, spot, and area. I
generally usually just use between uh
point and sun. Occasionally a spot lamp
if I'm doing I just want to like focus
on one specific thing. But I rarely use
an area lamp because there's not much
difference between that and a point lamp
with a radius essentially like making it
larger. Um but in our case we want to
look like a sun a sun lit. So I'm going
to check sun. And oh boy, we've got a
nuclear blast of sunlight. So, generally
I keep this around uh 10 cuz that's
actually what it like maxes out at when
you just like drag it over. It comes in
at 10. Um so that's yeah that's about
what we'll use. I also changed the
temperature which is I don't think I
think it was 4.5 they introduced this.
Um but yeah, you can now adjust this. So
this is a black body scale. So like the
closer like the lower this Kelvin scale
is the more it's like fire and like you
know incandescent bulb and then like
warm LED and then you can get to like
skylight and you can go all the way and
it's just like crazy blue. But anyways,
so sunlight um you know until it looks
right to you. [laughter]
Um I don't know something that's a bit
too much. Let's go. Oh boy. I don't even
know. I feel like I was just twisting
that too much. Now, I'm not actually
sure what looks like sunlamp. Anyways,
good thing is we can change it later if
we want to. Um, now the interesting
thing about a sunlamp is it doesn't
actually matter where it is positioned.
You can see if I position this close to
my donut or my thing like nothing
happens. Whereas a point lamp obviously
is very largely dependent on its
location cuz there is the inverse square
law where like light falls off at what
is it uh four times for every doubling
of distance. So a huge sharp falloff but
sun because it's so far away there's no
falloff and so it doesn't matter where
it actually is. So the only thing that
matters with sun is the rotation of it.
Right? So I'm just going to rotate that
to look like early morning sunshine.
Right? cuz it's going to, you know,
trying to tell a story with a donut.
It's challenging, but we're trying. So,
early morning, somebody's got their
coffee in a cafe or something. Um,
that's what we're going with. Oh, look
at that. My mug is just slightly off the
table. And now it is not. Excellent.
Now, this by itself is uh is pretty
boring, right? If you were to do a
render of this, which you can do just by
hitting uh F12, right? That's it's okay.
But it's like this feels too naked,
right? It's just being blasted with
light everywhere. It helps to try to
shape it and kind of highlight what is
important, which is these two elements.
The rest of the scene that can just
Yeah, it's not important to us, right?
So, we can throw that into shadow. Um,
and it's also an opportunity to make it
look like there's a a scene outside of
the view there, which you can do by
casting shadows um into the scene. So, I
want to basically set up two blockers to
make it look like this is shining in
through a window. Um, and as is typical
with uh with 3D, you don't have to model
the windows because we're not looking at
them. You they can just be blockers. So,
I'm going to hit shift A. And for my
blocker, I'm going to use a plane. Okay.
So, it brings in this. I'm gonna move it
over there. I'm going to go R and then
X. holding down control until it says 90
at the top of the screen there. Do a
single click. Um, all right. That is my
first blocker. And then I need another
blocker going uh this way. So I'm going
to have like a slither of light going
across there. So shift D. Move this to
Oh boy. Y then X
R Z to rotate it by 90°. And then here
we go.
like that. All right. And then I'll move
this one over a little bit. Maybe just
make it a little bit bigger.
Okay. To just try to shape it to just
get some of that light to be a little
bit more targeted. I'm also going to
move this mug just further in the back.
Um, so I'm going to hit G. And yeah, if
you want to lock something to a specific
act, like I want to move it along the X
and the Y, but not the Z. We talked
about this with scale, but applies for
everything. So, if I hit G and then
shift zed, it'll move it along the X and
the Y but not the Z. And so, this is an
easy way if like you've got, you know,
that it's touching the ground where it
needs to, but you just need to move it
around. You can quickly move things by G
and then shift Z and it'll move it
around the plane, but it won't lift it
off of the table, which is uh useful.
All right. And then I'll move my plate
over like so.
And yeah, that looks okay. All right.
Now, yeah, like I said, this this this
looks okay, but it also looks kind of a
little bit like film noir, right? And
what does film noir look like? Looks
fake. Looks very like curated and
designed in a comic strip, right? And
the big telltale for that is like we've
got almost complete darkness over here,
right? Um, and the real world is not
that like that. If this was a cafe, you
would have things bouncing off uh other
objects to the left hand side outside of
frame. But not only that, this is a
sunrise. It's not happening on Mars or
anything like that. So the sky is blue
generally speaking. So uh there needs to
be some blue light as well. So what I'm
going to do is Oh, look at this. We've
got our blockers and yeah, let's
actually move my light and my blockers.
So shift selecting those. I'm going to
hit M and I'm going to create a new
collection and I'm going to call this
lighting. Um, and then we can call these
two objects. By the way, if you want to
rename two objects and at once, uh, you
can do it by I was just trying to
remember the hot key. [laughter]
Uh, there you go. It's Ctrl F2. Um,
which is the same hotkey I think.
Actually, no, I don't think it is in
Windows, but anyways, Crl+ F2 and then
you can just say uh find and replace or
you can just say set name and then you
can say new and I can just call this
blockers or blocker and then just say
okay. And there we go. It's call it
blocker and then the other one
blocker.001. Okay, cool. So now I as I
said I want to create some skylighting.
So I'm going to add a new lamp or I
could duplicate the sun. I'll just
duplicate the sun. So, I'll move this
over to there. And I'm now going to hide
I'll call this one sun, right? My
original one. And then this new one I'm
going to call sky. And I'm going to
change this to be a point lamp. Like
this. Um, and now I'm going to disable
the sky. And this is actually a good tip
to do. It's a really uh bad trap that a
lot of beginners do is when they're
they're working with lighting, they end
up just kind of like throwing in lights.
But you have to work in isolation. You
should only be looking at each light
separately to understand what purpose it
actually has on the scene. So, hiding my
my sun lamp. I'm going to position this
up high because the sky is high even
though there would be like a window
there. Something about actually let's
just see the scale in relation to get
real mathematical here. The scale of the
donut in relation to how tall would the
window be? Maybe up to about here. I
don't know. Um about there, let's say.
And let's move it over a little bit.
Okay. And then
let's uh increase this. Let's remove the
tint. And instead, I'm going to make
this like you can actually like keep the
tint, right? And make it go like all the
way to that. But I want to have a little
bit more control over it. I might want
to make it look a little more purplish
or, you know, we're not going for
something entirely photorealistic. We're
going for like exaggerated realism. Um,
which can often look way better than
real realism. So, this you can see this
is a soft color. This is like
moonlighting, but it just needs to be a
little bit just so that there's the hint
that there is skylighting along with the
uh sun. Now, the other big factor that
it's missing is that the skylighting is
not casting shadows like this, right? If
the sun was away and it was just being
lit by like think of like an overcast
day, right? The sky itself, the entire
dome is the size of the light. So the
radius of our lamp here needs to
increase, right? By a lot. Now this uh
this is a very underused value like it's
one of the most important values when it
comes to lighting is the radius of
something because it's the softness of
the shadow. As an example, let's just
bring this in or actually hang on. Let's
just increase this so we can actually
see it. What can I do? Exposure. There
we go. All right. So, this is uh like
the default it comes in like this. Okay.
And you can see how harsh those shadows
are. So, as a as a rule, harsh shadow is
very good at revealing detail. So, we
often use a lot at polygon cuz we need
to show the the detail of textures along
a surface. So, if you want to highlight
the sprinkles or something like that,
you would use a very small radius like
this. So, it's really sharp um shadows.
Whereas if you want to reveal more of
the form and just the overall color of a
surface, that is when you would use a
larger radius, right? As a general rule
and it has a huge impact on uh on
lighting. The other big thing is is
distance. So there's I mentioned briefly
the inverse square law. Um a lot of
beginners, you know, they're going like,
oh, it's like skylighting. I'll just
position the lamp up here, right? The
problem with that is because of the
inverse square law, every doubling of
distance, so from like here to here,
right, is going to uh well, hang on.
From here to here, what am I thinking
of? But basically, like from the the mug
to the end of the donor, it could lose
something like a third of its energy.
Um, it's it's a it's just an uh what do
you call it? It's not something that is
obvious, but it is really really
important. So something needs to be far
away or appear to be far away. You got
to try to make it look really far away
basically. Um so you know something up
in up up in the air basically. All
right, let's clear that and let's
increase it and go back to the radius.
So nice large radius in the sky. You
know, it's not as big as the sky
actually is, but you know, something
like that. So we've got smooth lighting
over everything. And now with my sun.
Ha, look at that. We've got the tinge of
blue lighting in the air. Um, but we
have the lovely hot, warm sun uh coming
through as well. All right, the final
lamp that I need is that bounce lighting
for the rest of the cafe. So, I'm going
to duplicate my uh skylighting there.
And I'm going to position this. I mean,
you know, how what's the height of the
ceiling or what is it even bouncing off?
Who knows? There could be a wall here
and it's bouncing off that. This is more
where you get to control um you know
what what is it that you're actually
doing. So again, I'm going to hide my
sky, hide my sun. So I'm just looking at
this bounce lighting coming off the
wall. Um and I'm going to uh clear this
to make it look uh just like white
light. Um and by the way, if you want to
change something to the default value,
just mousing over a color here, just hit
backspace and now it goes to its default
value. I can also backspace on the power
and it goes to its default value of 10.
Um, so that's a handy one to know. And
again, I will
Yeah, I mean, I can have a little bit of
control over this cuz there could
actually be a lamp off in the distance
there. We don't really have a lot of
rules for this bounce one. I'm just
looking at trying to fill in the
darkness there. Right. Right there.
Because without it, and we'll call this
uh indoor bounce, right? If you don't
have it, it just looks too dark. So,
there needs to be something there just
to fill in this area of our donut. All
right. So, that's what I'm looking at
there. Something about that. Let's look
at it from the camera view. And I think
now my skylighting is uh a little bit
too blue. I'll dial it back a little
bit. I think it might actually be a
little bit too bright. So, let me just
dial that in. In which case, now I can
make it a little more saturated.
Pull it in.
Okay. How's that? Okay. That's the sun.
That is the indoor by itself.
Okay. All right. And that's pretty good.
That is not bad. Now, you can play with
it a little bit. Um, but that's
generally we've got it in the right
place. Now, I'm going to move my camera
in a little closer. So, I'm going to
check this little uh camera view thing.
And, uh, sorry, lock toggle lock to uh,
camera view. And now I'm just going to
move around and just pull the camera in
a little bit just so we've got a tighter
view of our donut. And then again, just
make sure you uncheck that so that we
can uh move around freely without it
interrupting. Okay. Now, some of you
might be wondering, how can we improve
this so it doesn't look crap? [laughter]
Because what we are using right now, um,
this is called the EV rendering engine.
And it's the reason we've got this kind
of fuzzy noise to our shadows. It's the
reason we have some of our objects are
not really casting much of a shadow in
our scene. Um, and it's also the reason
you might notice that as you like rotate
around, right, you got like wow, look at
this like bright lighting on the plane
here. And watch what happens as I move
the camera. Just disappears. [laughter]
So Eevee is a game engine. So it's doing
a lot of game hackery and that means it
is largely it is due to being screen
space meaning that it's doing bounce
lighting here. Okay. So it's bouncing
the off the plane onto this wall here.
However, it's it's only visible um it
can only see what the camera sees. So
it's called screen space. And that means
that the moment that this moves away and
we no longer have that bright light
reflecting off there, it doesn't know
that that plane exists and that
something should bounce up there. So, it
can result in these like large changes
of lighting. It's kind of the biggest
issue if you're making animations um and
the cameras flying through some spaces
and you don't want to have lighting kind
of changing all over the place. I've got
a whole video on EV if you want to watch
that. Um I talk all about this and go
into more detail. Um but, you know,
these are kind of one of the biggest
limitations. Now, the main thing you
should be trying to do if you're using
the EV rendering engine is the default
value right here for steps is wrong.
Like there's no reason it should be that
low. Steps, you could think of this like
accuracy. Um, now if I increase this to
16, which is the maximum value, look at
how much better those shadows are.
Right? This is the before and then this
is the after. Okay? And it's even more
stark here, right? Look at look at how
much more connected that is. And then if
I go back to here, look at all this
extra crap, right? It's it's basically
an accuracy amount and it should be
maxed out unless you're working on a
really really poor computer and it
happens to stall it or something, you
know, but even then you you double it at
least go to 12. Um, but that by itself
will improve the look of shadows. Um,
the other thing as well is my icing. I
just want to check. Okay. Oh no, that's
the sprinkles.
Okay. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. So,
I think I said that I had the scale of
my icing too high on my donut. I think a
03 looks good. And on my sprinkles, I'm
also going to drop that. I'll make it
06.
Nope. Nope. Nope. Let's go 08. So, we
want a little bit, you know, this is a
little bit of pass through here, but not
a crazy amount or else. Yeah. [snorts]
And that's this is quite common to do,
right? If you're making something, you
might set a value when you're in one
state of Blender and then when you add
in lighting from, you know, a more
extreme like sunlight coming in, you
start to notice that some materials
actually, yeah, it doesn't look good.
Um, and so you need to adjust it. And
that's a totally fine thing to do. Um,
there's not really any way uh around it.
Now, the fuzziness, this fuzziness that
you can see right here, um, that is a
result of the samples. So samples you
can think of I mean it's it's like
samples per pixel on a screen and like
basically the more samples you have the
clearer it's going to be. Now what
you're actually looking at right now is
the viewport samples which is set to 16.
When you do your render it will kick in
and use this amount which is 64. So see
how fuzzy it looks there. I do my render
and it comes in not so fuzzy. There is
still fuzz. There's always going to be a
little bit of fuzz, but at least it's
not uh, you know, crazy, but yeah, if
you want to increase it, you can uh, you
know, double that or whatnot. You can
have fun with that. Another thing that
can improve the realism of an EV render
is using a light probe. So, as I
mentioned with the light bouncing off
here, as it fluctuates around, it's kind
of throwing light as it goes around. But
the other issue is that for example um
the the it doesn't actually know that
light is hitting the underside of the
donut here and it would blast out in
that direction because it can't see what
is behind the donut right now. It also
can't see um uh like light that would be
hitting the edge of this plate here and
then bouncing it back this way, right?
It can't see it because from where the
camera is, it just can't see those
objects. So, if you wanted to um add
that, you could add in a light probe
volume. So, I'll show you what that
looks like. Uh first of all, I'll just
shift rightclick on my donut just so
that that's the point it comes in at.
I'm going to say shift a light probe
volume. So, this will cast like a grid
of ping pong balls over your scene. And
I say ping-pong balls cuz I'll show you
what they look like soon. Um, but
basically you want to scale this to look
to kind of encapsulate everything you've
got in the scene. And we've got way too
much vertically, so I don't need all
that much there. Um, and you want the
ping pong balls, these little balls to
be sitting just above the surface of the
table. Again, I go into way more detail
in my EV video, which you could watch if
you were interested in this. You really
want to dive into EV, by all means. Um,
I think I probably only need about
three. No, I'll go four. Why not? Um,
okay. And then now that you've got this,
if you hit the bake light c, you'll see
that the scene gets a little bit
brighter. So, this is how it looked
before and this is how it looks after.
And you can uh improve this a lot by
just like shuffling the balls around.
So, that now I've got one ball that is
going to be, let's say,
let's go a little bit. Oh boy. Here and
here. So, I've got one that's going to
be resting right on the edge of that
plate there. And I want one inside the
donut. All right. And now, let's do that
now. All right. And now we've got more
bounce coming from there. So, each of
these you can think of like little lamps
that are going through the scene and
able to see things from the other side
that the camera cannot. So, it's able to
break that limitation of something being
screen space. And you can see that looks
better. So, this is with the light probe
on. And then if I was to turn my probe
off and do another render. So this is
with it off. This is with it on. All
right. So very big difference.
Definitely worthwhile having a light
probe if that's what you're going to use
uh to do your render. Uh and by the way,
if you want to visualize what they can
see and uh underneath viewport display,
you can enable data and then each of
these points become little ping pong
balls. That's why I think of them like
that. Um, and you can see the actual
light that was captured at each one of
those points and, uh, essentially, yeah,
what light it's going to be throwing out
into the rest of the scene. And the
final thing that's going to make a big
difference to your final render here,
um, and one of the big reasons that this
feels like a, you know, a CG computer
graphics render is that right now
everything has the same amount of focus.
And that is physically impossible with a
real camera. There's no way to have
something that doesn't have um depth of
field unless you were using a pinhole
camera, believe it or not. Um but
anyways, so to get that look, to get
depth of field, we're going to select
our camera object in our outliner and
then down here there is a checkbox for
depth of field. And ooh already it's
starting to look cool. Now you just
select the object that you want to be in
focus. So you click the little eyropper
tool and then you want to click on the
object. Now, if you've got what I have
here, you can see it's always clicking
on the volume um because it thinks that
the volume is in front of it. But
anyways, yeah, I can now just click on
my icing object there. And um you can
see now this is the before and then this
is after. So you can see in the
background there that noisy uh you know
concrete texture that isn't relevant to
the viewer um is now buttery smooth. And
that's a really nice way to not only
make something look more realistic, but
also to guide the viewer to what is
important cuz that is one of the biggest
problems you have as an artist is you're
giving somebody an entire image and
you're trying to tell them like what is
the important bits like what should they
be looking at and they don't know if
everything has just got like hyper noise
and detail and color and everything. So
you're trying to guide it and that's one
of the tools uh to do that. And one
final other tip as well. Um cuz the the
biggest like downside to using EV is
like the shadows just don't feel crisp
enough. They don't feel like tight
enough to the object. It's kind of a
little bit too it's a little bit too
blurry. If you select a lamp like this
one here, the sun lamp, and then you go
to your shadow settings here, there is a
box that says jitter. And you won't see
any change in the viewport unless you
were to go to your viewport settings and
enable jittered shadows. But I don't
think you should cuz it's just when
you've got that enabled just like every
time you move it, it just jitters around
and it's super annoying. But if I was to
do another render now, you will see that
the shadows just feel a little bit more
accurate, especially in the background
there, right? Um, and essentially it's
uh I believe it's like rendering each
like multiple versions of the lamp at
like because it's got a radius on it, a
little soft radius. Um, so enabling
jitter can work a lot better for like
soft lamps like what we've got here. So,
um, there you go. So, that's one of the
other tips. But if you want to go very
realistic and you want to avoid the
light probes, you want to avoid all
these settings like jitter and all this
kind of thing and you just want to you
just want to make something and then
just have it come out beautifully, then
you should be using a different
rendering engine. You should be using
cycles, cycles, cycles, cycles.
Now, my recording has slowed down
because it's using my CPU. Um, this is
cycles. Now, I'll actually uh I'm going
to just turn that off for a sec cuz it's
slowing down my computer. The first
thing you should check if you want to
use cycles because some of you just
tried that then and much like my
computer, I don't know if you can hear
that, but it has started to wor up. the
fans are like, "Whoa, this is using
maximum uh maximum heat." Right? So,
first of all, go to your edit and go to
preferences and then go to system. Then
at the top there, you've got cycles
render devices. Um, what you want to see
is if you have any graphics card on your
computer that you can use to render, you
should be using it. So, if you've got an
Nvidia card, you would be clicking CUDA
or optics. Optics is preferable. So, if
you've got a card that supports optics,
use the optics one. HIP is for AMD
cards. Open API is for Intel, I believe.
And then metal. You'll see metal if
you've got a Mac. Um, in my case, I've
got a uh Overkill RTX Pro 6000 Blackwell
Workstation Edition, which I just got,
given to me by the kind folks at Dell.
They gave me a Whisbang um Dell T2 Pro,
and uh it's amazing. I think it costs
like $20,000 or something stupid. Just
the card by itself, I think, is like
15,000. It's It's ridiculous. It's
obviously enterprise and prolevel. But
for the three people watching this that
happen to own a studio, if you really
want to deck it out and give artists
stuff that they'll never have to worry
about render times, this is the card. It
is amazing. So, if you've got one of
those cards, use it. And then make sure
here where it says device, you want to
make sure instead of CPU, it is using uh
GPU instead.
And now you can see how much faster that
is. Right now this is in 4K on my
computer and this is the size of the
window here. If you want to like speed
up your render, you can also just change
the size of the window, right? I can
drop the size of this like this, right?
So, it's only going to be rendering on
how much it can see here, right? So, as
I move around, you can see it's much
faster now because the size of that
window is so much smaller. Um, so that's
another thing you can do if you want to
be able to move around whilst it's uh
whilst it's rendering. Now, the
fuzziness that you can see here, that is
samples. So it's still the same term
samples. But the difference is is that
cycles is a path tracer, not a
rasterized engine like uh uh EV. So path
tracing means that you don't have to
deal with any probes or anything like
that. It can see what is behind the
donut. It can see between the sprinkles.
So it's actually casting like a bounce
off this sprinkle into that sprinkle
into that one. It's also doing it on the
other side of the doughut that we can't
see. It's actually shooting rays from
the camera out into the scene and
whatever it hits, it's collecting that
information. So, it is much more
physically accurate. It is the gold
standard for rendering um that um you
know computer graphics researchers use
and you know every movie VFX shot is
generally nowadays using path traces. It
results in a way better image but
obviously you have to pay for it with
render times. Now, one thing as well is
uh this noise that you can see here when
we do our render, it's going to kick in
a D noiseise, which is going to clear
that up. But you can also enable it in
your viewport. And then as you move
around, you can see that it's uh it's
still got like a little squiggle to it.
Um but it is uh it's obviously much
clearer and it's easier to see things uh
with that on. But now that I've got
that, I can do a render. It's going to
load in everything. The first time you
use Cycles, by the way, it might be
slow. Um, especially the first time if
you use a card like an Nvidia card or
AMD or anything like that, it will be
slower. Um, but after that, it should be
relatively quick. I say relatively
quick. I've got the fastest card
available right now. And you can see
it's no longer instantaneous. It is well
over 20 seconds. There we go. 23
seconds. Okay. But the difference,
right? Like if I go to right EV
like there is a big difference there. I
mean, actually, that was um before I did
the jitter. Let's let me just let's
really compare apples to apples. Okay,
there we go. But yeah, there there
definitely is a big difference,
especially in the shadows, um especially
in the reflections. So, there's it's a
noticeable difference, but it's also a
noticeable difference in the time,
right? The EV1 is less than a second.
The Cycles one is 23 seconds, and that's
on the fastest uh card available. So,
you're going to pay for it. And this
matters most when you're doing
animations because how many frames is
there in 1 second of footage? Generally
24 to 30. Um I'm actually recording in
60 frames right now. So that would be uh
30 frames a second. So 30 * 23 just to
get 1 second of footage. So if you're
doing an animation, that's where EV
really um can speed up your workflow.
But also like Eevee is just so much more
accessible. Part of the reason I stuck
to Eevee for all this tutorial up until
now is that uh I learned from uh talking
to people who did the previous donut
that some people's renders were taking
like over 20 minutes. Some people were
over an hour to do one single image of
the donut. And I couldn't believe it. I
just I I thought, "All right, we have to
use Eevee then because there's just no
way people are going to be able to
finish this thing." So Eevee definitely
can get a great result. Um, it's not
going to be as good as cycles, but like
I said, the times, you can't beat it.
It's so much faster. Um, so there's no
shame in uh using it if you don't have a
computer that uh can't do cycles. Now,
you can experiment with your lighting.
You can experiment with your scene. You
can add in different assets. You can
change the colors, make a whole bunch of
different variants. If you want to go
further, you know what I'm going to say.
I have released a course and it is
designed for people literally in your
shoes right now that have just finished
the donut and they want to know what
they can do next to improve and learn
more about Blender. So this course it's
called the beginners academy and it
teaches you the core essential Blender
skills which is modeling, texturing,
shading, lighting, camera and rendering.
And although we touched on all of those
in this series, that's really just the
tip of the iceberg because there's so
many different techniques to modeling.
There's so many different approaches to
texturing and to rendering and to
lighting. And we go through all in much
more detail in this course. So if you
finish this donut and you want to go off
and learn by yourself, there is a whole
YouTube full of tutorials out there. But
if you want something that is targeted,
more comprehensive, and will walk you
through the 8020, the 80% of Blender's
uh tools and techniques that you use 20%
of the time, then this is the course for
you. All taught by me, uh all taught
using the latest Blender 5.0. Um and I
hope that you will uh enjoy it.
Otherwise, thank you for watching this
entire series. If you want to join the
course, you can click the link below.